Norman H. Finkelstein Papers 2001.0115
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Norman H. Finkelstein Papers
undated, 1983-2007
2001.0115
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
9.55 Linear feet
Norman H. Finkelstein is a Massachusetts-based writer of nonfiction for children and adults.The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, galleys, proofs and further editorial material pertaining to the author's career and his 16 published and 19 unpublished works.
Finkelstein, Norman H.
Biography
Norman H. Finkelstein is a Massachusetts-based writer of nonfiction for children and adults. He is the recipient of the Golden Kite Honor Book Award for Nonfiction, for With Heroic Truth: The Life of Edward R. Murrow, and two National Jewish Book Awards, for Forged in Freedom: Shaping the Jewish American Experience and Heeding the Call:Jewish Voices in America's Civil Rights Struggle.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, galleys, proofs and further editorial material pertaining to the author's career and both his published and unpublished works.
Arrangement
Series I: Published and Unpublished Works ( undated, 1983-2007 )
Series II: Correspondence, Presentations, Awards, and Media ( undated, 1984-2005 )
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
American Jewish History Dodd C 10194
Ariel Sharon Dodd A 9724
Plastics Dodd C 10195
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Finkelstein, Norman H.; Artwork.; Audio visual materials.; Author.; Authors, American--Biography.; Books.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Galley proofs.; Manuscripts.; Northeast Children's Literature Collection.; Notes.; Page proofs.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Publications.; Speeches.; Typescripts.
- Series I: Published and Unpublished Works, undated, 1983-2007
  - Subseries A: Unpublished Works, undated, 1987-2000
    - First one foot, then the other, undated, [1987-1991]
      - Rejection letters, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Levine and his flying machine, undated, [1990-1991]
      - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Uncle Carol and the Bessarundian Connection, undated, [1990-1991]
      - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Story text, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - By hook or by crook, undated, [1991]
      - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Tanta Tanya, undated, [1991]
      - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Entertainers, undated
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Clara strikes, 1995-1997
      - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Israel 1948, 1995-1996
      - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - What's news?, 1995-1998
      - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Point of Order, 1996-1997
      - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Years of Fear, 1996
      - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Revolutionary life of Paul Revere, 1997-1999
      - Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Calling out the troops: how and why America goes to war, 1998
      - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Genghis Khan Hotel, 1998-1999
      - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - On Stage [Back Stage], 1998
      - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Berlin: Cold War hot spot, 1999-2000
      - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Good Police Chief, 1999
      - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - How I became President of the United States, 1999
      - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The Flower Shop Cafe, 2000
      - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Subseries B: Published Works, undated, 1985-2007
    - Remember not to forget: a memory of the Holocaust, 1985, reprinted 1993, 2004
      - Outline, speech, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
        General note
        Precursors to the book
      - Rejection letters, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
        Includes one returned manuscript
      - Original manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Galley proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Galley proofs with editor's markings, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Reprint correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Theodor Herzl [: architect of a nation], 1987, revised edition 1991
      - Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        Mostly concerns the publication of the revised edition
      - Proposal, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Draft with editor's markings, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Draft with editor's markings, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Master galley proofs, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - F & G, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Permissions, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Master galley, undated (Box 13)
    - Emperor General: a biography of Douglas MacArthur, 1989
      - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Proposal, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Draft with editor's markings, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Draft, 3rd revision, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Photographic credits, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Heeding the call: Jewish voices in America's civil rights struggle, 1997-1999
      - Draft, "Draft #1,", 1997 (Box 6, Folder 70)
      - Draft, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - Drafts of flap copy, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - Photographic page proofs, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - Reviews, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - The Other 1492: Jewish settlement in the New World, 1987-1989
      - Correspondence, permissions, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Draft with editor's markings, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Draft, "Final draft #2,", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Galley proofs [2 copies], undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Publicity materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Captain of Innocence: France & the Dreyfus affair, 1991
      - Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Original manuscript, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Draft, "Draft #2,", 1991 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Draft, "Final draft,", 1991 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Index draft and galley, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Edited galley proofs, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Edited galley proofs, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Page proofs, undated (Box 12, Folder 52)
      - Dustjacket mock-up, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Permissions, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Dustjackets [5 copies], undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Uncorrected proof, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Page proofs, undated (Box 13)
    - Sounds in the air: the golden age of radio, 1990-1993
      - Proposal, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
        Original title: Is Everybody Happy?: [The Legendary Stars of] Radio's Golden Age
      - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - Draft with editor's markings, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - Draft, "Draft #1,", 1991 (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - Draft, "Final draft,", 1991 (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Galley proofs, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - Uncorrected proof, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - Dustjacket, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Thirteen days/ninety miles: the Cuban missile crisis, 1991-1994
      - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - Draft, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      - Draft with editor's markings, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - Uncorrected proof [2 copies, one is unbound signatures], undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - Dustjacket [2 copies], undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - With heroic truth: the life of Edward R. Murrow, 1991-1988
      - Correspondence, 1991-1998 (Box 7, Folder 74)
      - Chapter outline, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
      - Research materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
      - Draft, with editor's markings, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 76)
      - Draft, with editor's markings, undated, [1994] (Box 7, Folder 77)
      - Draft, with editor's markings, undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
      - Draft, with editor's markings, undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
      - Permissions, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - Dustjacket, undated (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Friends indeed: the special relationship of Israel and the United States, 1997-1998
      - Draft, with editor's markings, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 83)
      - Draft, with copyeditor's markings, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 84)
      - Galley, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 85)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - The Way things never were: the truth about the "good old days", 1995-2000
      - Proposal (2 copies), undated (Box 8, Folder 86)
      - Correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 87)
      - Original manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 88)
      - Draft, first pass proofs with copyeditor's marks, undated (Box 8, Folder 89)
      - Editorial materials, undated (Box 8, Folder 89)
      - Final draft, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 90)
        With photo galley proofs bound in
      - Photo permissions, undated (Box 9, Folder 91)
      - Photo proofs, undated (Box 9, Folder 91)
      - Advance reviewer copy, undated (Box 9, Folder 92)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - Forged in freedom: shaping the Jewish-American experience, 2001-2002
      - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 94)
      - Draft, with editor's markings, undated (Box 9, Folder 95)
      - Edited page proofs, undated (Box 9, Folder 96)
      - First pass proofs, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 97)
      - Final proofs, undated (Box 12, Folder 98)
      - Promotional materials, undated (Box 9, Folder 99)
      - Final proof, 2002 (Box 13)
      - Preliminary proof, 2002 (Box 13)
    - Ariel Sharon, 2003-2005
      - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 100)
      - Original manuscript, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 101)
      - First draft, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 102)
      - Draft, with editor's markings, "first pass,", 2003 (Box 9, Folder 103)
      - Draft, with editor's markings, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 104)
      - Draft with editor's markings, undated (Box 10, Folder 105)
      - Final draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 106)
      - Page proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
      - Publicity materials, undated (Box 10, Folder 108)
      - Permissions, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 108)
      - Page proofs, 2005 (Box 13)
    - American Jewish History, 2006-2007
      - Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 10, Folder 109)
      - Proposal, undated (Box 10, Folder 110)
      - Expanded proposal, undated (Box 10, Folder 111)
      - Preliminary draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 112)
      - Preliminary draft #1 with editor's markings, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 113)
      - Preliminary draft #2 with thematic outline by chapter, undated (Box 10, Folder 114)
      - First draft, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 115)
      - Draft with editor's markings, "working edit,", 2007 (Box 11, Folder 116)
      - Final draft, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 117)
      - Page proofs, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 118)
      - Permissions, undated (Box 11, Folder 119)
      - Advance Reading Copy, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - Plastics, 2007
      - Publicity materials, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 121)
    - Three across: the great transatlantic air race of 1927, 1994-2008
      - Correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box 12, Folder 122)
      - Book, publication, correspondence, manuscript, dummy, 1994-2008 (Box 14)
      - Research notes, computer disk (final draft), PDFs (3), drafts (3), printed photographic reproductions "Columbia," postcards, paperback 1st edition, n.d., 1994-2002 (Box 14)
- Series II: Correspondence, Presentations, Awards, and Media, undated, 1984-2000
  - Professional correspondence, undated, 1997-2000 (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Public appearances, undated, 1997-2000 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Articles, undated, 1985-2000 (Box 12, Folder 125)
- Series III: 2010 Accession, undated, 2010
  - Jewish comedy stars: classic to cutting edge (Minneapolis: Kar-Ben Publishing, 2010), undated, 2010 (Box 15)
    Scope and Content Note
    Correspondence, Manuscript, Prints, Postcards Dates: 2008-2010 Organization: Labeled Folders Subjects: "Jewish Comedy All-Stars"